贵州省二零二五年初中学业水平考试中考英语听力测试，现在开始。第一节：听下面六段对话，选择与每段对话内容相符的图片。每段对话读一遍。一、
Hey Jen, have you got any pets?
Yes, I have a cat.
It's very cute.
2. What did you do last weekend, Wendy?
Well, I looked after my grandma at home.
3. Hello madam, can I help you?
Yes, please. I'm looking for a pair of socks.
4. Bill, what are you going to perform in our school art festival?
I'll play the guitar.
Jack, look! Whose basketball is this?
It might be Tom's.
He likes playing basketball very much.
6. me, is there hospital nearby?
Yes, turn right at the first crossing.
You'll see it next to the
第二节：听下面六个句子，选择与每个句子匹配的最佳应答。每个句子读一遍。
7. Nessie, what's your favourite colour?
8. Ben, thank you for helping me.
9. Sandy, how often do you go swimming?
10. Kevin, where are you going to live in the future?
11. Dave, what does your new maths teacher look like?
12. Helen, how do you improve your English?
第三节，听下面六段对话。每段对话后有一个小题，根据对话内容及问题，选择最佳选项。每段对话读两遍。
Steve, you look tired.
Anything wrong? 14.
didn't sleep well last night.
Now I have a terrible headache.
14. sleep well last night.
Li Mei, what do Chinese people usually do on the Dragon Boat Festival?
We often watch Dragon Boat races and make zongzi.
And watching the races is my favourite.
15. Uncle Sam, it's cloudy and cool in today.
How 16. how's the weather in New York?
It's raining cats and dogs, so we all stay at home.
16. Jenny, how will you go to Guangzhou to spend your holiday?
I plan to fly there, but the price is kind of high.
17. Mike, you know our school rules.
Don't play football
18. Excuse me, may I take your order, sir?
Yes, a large bowl of beef noodles, please.
Excuse me, may I take your order, sir?
第四节，听下面三段对话，每段对话后有两个小题，根据对话内容及问题，选择最佳选项。每段对话读两遍。听下面一段对话，回答第十九、二十两个小题。
What the government is doing to protect them?
Oh, I'd like to see it.
I'm doing my homework about that.
What time will it start?
At four o So when and where shall we meet?
At half past three, outside the cinema.
Okay, see you then.
See you. Hi, Tony speaking.
Hi, Tony. It's Mary.
Do you want to see a film this afternoon?
Thank you for inviting me.
What is it about?
It's about animals in danger and what the government is doing to protect them.
Oh, I'd like to see it.
I'm doing my homework about that.
What time will it start?
At four o So when and where shall we meet?
At half past three, outside the cinema.
Okay, see you then.
See you. conversation.
听下面一段对话，回答第二十一、二十二两个小题。
Peter, we need to clean our house.
Your grandma is coming over this evening.
Okay, what are we going to do?
Let's clean up the kitchen first.
I can sweep the floor and take out the rubbish.
Could you please do the dishes?
Sure, mom. And I can also wash my clothes and tidy my room.
Good. Let me see.
I'll clean the living room before your grandma arrives.
Peter, we need to clean our house.
Your grandma is coming over this evening.
Okay, what are we going to do?
Let's clean up the kitchen first.
I can sweep the floor and take out the rubbish.
Could you please do the dishes?
Sure, mom. And I can also wash my clothes and tidy my room.
Good. Let me see.
I'll clean the living room before your grandma arrives.
听下面一段对话，回答第二十三、二十四两个小题。
questions He was away for a month because of his job.
We want to give him a nice welcome home dinner.
I see. Then what food does your father like?
He likes beef, fish, and fruit salad.
I'll prepare all of them, and my mom will make a chocolate cake.
Sounds great. Your dad must be very happy.
Hey, Lily, what are you doing?
I'm making a food list for my dad's welcome home dinner.
Oh, is your dad coming home soon?
Yes, he will be back tomorrow.
He was away for a month because of his job.
We want to give him a nice welcome home dinner.
I see. Then what food does your father like?
He likes beef, fish, and fruit salad.
I'll prepare all of them, and my mom will make a chocolate cake.
Sounds great. Your dad must be very happy.
5. time, We will go to the computer museum.
第五节，听下面一段独白，根据独白内容完成图表所缺信息，每空请填一词，读三遍。
I will pass out the school trip forms today.
Please bring your forms back to me by Friday.
remember to wear comfortable shoes because we will walk to
Finally, please bring some food for lunch because the museum doesn't provide it.
On June 30th, we will leave the school at 8 o in the morning, and we should be back
by 5 o in the afternoon.
Classes will be cancelled because of this school trip.
Okay, those are all the announcements for today.
Everyone, please open your books to page 78.
Attention, class! I'll be introducing next week's school trip,
so please listen carefully.
We will go to the computer museum.
I will pass out the school trip forms today.
Please bring your forms back to me by Friday.
Besides, remember to wear comfortable shoes because we will walk to
Finally, please bring some food for lunch because the museum doesn't provide it.
June 30th, we will leave the school at 8 o in the morning, and we should be back by
5 o in the afternoon.
Classes will be cancelled because of this school trip.
Okay, those are all the announcements for today.
Everyone, please open your books to page 78.
Attention, class! I'll be introducing next week's school trip, so please listen
carefully. We will go to the computer museum.
I will pass out the school trip forms today.
Please bring your forms back to me by Friday.
Besides, remember to wear comfortable shoes because we will walk to
Finally, please bring some food for lunch because the museum doesn't provide it.
On June 30th, we will leave the school at 8 o in the morning, and we should be back
by 5 o in the afternoon.
Classes will be cancelled because of this school trip.
Okay, those are all the announcements for today.
Everyone, please open your books to page 78.
is of
听力测试。到此结束。